<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Saint Petersburg City Guide</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    //Tab name
    <string name="tab_museum">Museums</string>
    <string name="tab_palace">Palaces</string>
    <string name="tab_religion">Religion</string>
    <string name="tab_theatre">Theatres</string>

    <string name="showMap">Show On Map</string>

    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    // Museums
    <string name="annotation_russian">Russian Museum</string>
    <string name="annotation_aurora">Russian Cruiser Aurora</string>
    <string name="annotation_dostoyevsky">Dostoyevsky Museum</string>
    <string name="annotation_hermitage">Hermitage</string>
    <string name="annotation_kunstkamera">Kunstkamera</string>
    <string name="annotation_zoological">Zoological Museum</string>
    //Palaces
    <string name="annotation_moika">Moika Palace</string>
    <string name="annotation_winter">Winter Palace</string>
    <string name="annotation_pavlovsk">Pavlovsk Palace</string>
    <string name="annotation_menshikov">Menshikov Palace</string>
    <string name="annotation_peterhof">Peterhof Palace</string>
    <string name="annotation_stroganov">Stroganov Palace</string>
    //Religion
    <string name="annotation_aleksander">Alexander Nevsky Lavra</string>
    <string name="annotation_isaacs">Saint Isaac\'s Cathedral</string>
    <string name="annotation_kazan">Kazan Cathedral</string>
    <string name="annotation_kronstadt">Kronstadt Naval Cathedral</string>
    <string name="annotation_savior">Church of the Savior on Blood</string>
    <string name="annotation_smolny">Smolny Convent</string>
    //Theatre
    <string name="annotation_aleksandrinsky">Alexandrinsky Theatre</string>
    <string name="annotation_theatre_hermitage">Hermitage Theatre</string>
    <string name="annotation_mariinsky">Mariinsky Theatre</string>
    <string name="annotation_mikhaylovsky">Mikhailovsky Theatre</string>
    <string name="annotation_music">Theatre of Musical Comedy</string>
    <string name="annotation_opera">Chamber Opera</string>
    //MainText
    <string name="museum_russian">The State Russian Museum (formerly the Russian
Museum of His Imperial Majesty Alexander III) is the largest depository of Russian fine art
in Saint Petersburg. It is also one of the largest museums in the country.\n
\n
The museum was established on April 13, 1895, upon enthronement of Nicholas II to
commemorate his father, Alexander III. Its original collection was composed of artworks taken
from the Hermitage Museum, Alexander Palace, and the Imperial Academy of Arts. After
the Russian Revolution of 1917, many private collections were nationalized and relocated to the
Russian Museum. These included Kazimir Malevich\'s Black Square.\n
\n
The main building of the museum is the Mikhailovsky Palace, a splendid Neoclassical residence
of Grand Duke Michael Pavlovich, erected in 1819-25 to a design by Carlo Rossi on Square of
Arts in St Petersburg. Upon the death of the Grand Duke the residence was named after his
wife as the Palace of the Grand Duchess Elena Pavlovna, and became famous for its many
theatrical presentations and balls.</string>
    
    <string name="museum_aurora">Aurora (Russian: Авро́ра, tr. Avrora; IPA: [ɐˈvrorə]) is a 1900
Russian protected cruiser, currently preserved as a museum ship in St. Petersburg. Aurora was
one of three Pallada-class cruisers, built in St. Petersburg for service in the Pacific. All three
ships of this class served during the Russo-Japanese War. Aurora survived the Battle of
Tsushima and was interned under US protection in the Philippines, eventually returned to
the Baltic Fleet. The second ship, Pallada, was sunk by the Japanese at Port Arthur in 1904. The
third ship, Diana, was interned in Saigon after the Battle of the Yellow Sea. One of the first
incidents of the October Revolution in Russia took place on the cruiser Aurora.\n
\n
As a museum ship, the cruiser Aurora became one of the many tourist attractions of Leningrad
(now Saint Petersburg), and continued to be a symbol of the October Socialist Revolution and a
prominent attribute of Russian history. In addition to the museum space, a part of the ship
continued to house a naval crew whose duties included caring for the ship, providing security and
participating in government and military ceremonies.</string>
    
    <string name="museum_dostoevsky">The F. M. Dostoyevsky Literary Memorial
Museum (Государственный Литературно-мемориальный музей Ф. М. Достоевского), located
on Kuznechny Lane 5/2 in Saint Petersburg, was opened on November 12, 1971 in the former
apartment of the famous writer. Fyodor Dostoyevsky lived in the apartment twice during his life:
first for a short period in 1846 in the beginnings of his career, and later from October 1878 until
his death in January 1881. The apartment was his home during the composition of some of his
most notable works, including The Double: A Petersburg Poem and The Brothers
Karamazov. The apartment has been reconstructed based on the memoirs of his wife and his
friends.\n
\n
The Dostoyevsky Museum has several parts:\n
- The Writer’s Memorial Apartment – the museum\'s central part\n
- The Literary Exhibit, dedicated to the writer\'s biography and creation\n
- The Exhibit Halls, for exhibits of contemporary art\n
- The Theater, in which the White Theater presents its performances, as well as the museum\'s
partner theaters: \"Puppet Format\", \"Takoy Theatre\", and other local, national, and
international theaters.\n
\n
Every November, the museum hosts an international scholarly conference \"Dostoyevsky and
World Culture\" and a journal of the same name is published with the conference proceedings.</string>
    
    <string name="museum_hermitage">The State Hermitage
Museum (Russian: Госуда́рственный Эрмита́ж, tr. Gosudárstvennyj
Ermitáž; IPA: [ɡɐsʊˈdarstvʲɪnɨj ɛrmʲɪˈtaʂ]) is a museum of art and culture in Saint
Petersburg, Russia. One of the largest and oldest museums in the world, it was founded in 1764
by Catherine the Great and has been open to the public since 1852. Its collections, of which only
a small part is on permanent display, comprise over three million items (the numismatic collection
accounts for about one third of them) including the largest collection of paintings in the world.
The collections occupy a large complex of six historic buildings along Palace Embankment,
including the Winter Palace, a former residence of Russian emperors. Apart from them,
the Menshikov Palace, Museum of Porcelain, Storage Facility at Staraya Derevnya and the
eastern wing of the General Staff Building are also part of the museum. The museum has several
exhibition centers abroad. The Hermitage is a federal state property. Since July 1992, the
director of the museum has been Mikhail Piotrovsky.\n
\n
Of six buildings of the main museum complex, five, named the Winter Palace, Small Hermitage,
Old Hermitage, New Hermitage and Hermitage Theatre, are open to the public. The entrance
ticket for foreign tourists costs more than the fee paid by citizens of Russia and Belarus.
However, entrance is free of charge the first Thursday of every month for all visitors, and free
daily for students and children. The museum is closed on Mondays. The entrance for individual
visitors is located in the Winter Palace, accessible from the Courtyard.</string>
    
    <string name="museum_kunstkamera">The Kunstkamera (or Kunstkammer; Russian: Кунсткамера) is the first museum in Russia.
Established by Peter the Great and completed in 1727, the Kunstkammer Building hosts
the Peter the Great Museum of Anthropology and Ethnography (Russian: Музей
антропологии и этнографии имени Петра Великого Российской академии наук), with a
collection of almost 2,000,000 items. It is located on the Universitetskaya Embankment in Saint
Petersburg, facing the Winter Palace.\n
\n
The Kunstkamera was established by Peter the Great on the Neva Riverfront. The
turreted Petrine Baroque building of the Kunstkamera designed by Georg Johann
Mattarnovy was completed by 1727. The foundation stone for the Kunstkammer was laid in
1719.\n
Peter\'s museum was a cabinet of curiosities dedicated to preserving \"natural and human
curiosities and rarities\", a very typical type of collection in the period. The tsar\'s personal
collection, originally stored in the Summer Palace, features a large assortment of human and
animal fetuses with anatomical deficiencies, which Peter had seen in 1697 visiting Frederick
Ruysch and Levinus Vincent. The underlying idea of their kunstkammers was to acquire full
knowledge of the world. The Dutch word \"kunst-kamer\" seems to be introduced by the
surgeon Stephanus Blankaart in 1680.\n
The Kunstkamera of Peter the Great is often seen as a haphazard collection of incoherent
rarities, but it seems they were collected systematically subject to a well defined plan. Peter\'s
main interest was in \"naturalia\", rather than the so-called \"artificialia\". Peter encouraged research
of deformities, all along trying to debunk the superstitious fear of monsters. He issued
an ukase ordering malformed, still-born infants to be sent from all over the country to the imperial
collection. He subsequently had them put on show in the Kunstkamera as examples of accidents
of nature.\n
In 1716 Peter established the mineral cabinet of Kunstkamera, depositing there a collection of
1195 minerals which he had bought from Gotvald, a Danzig doctor. The collection was enriched
with Russian minerals. It was a predecessor of the Fersman Mineralogical Museum, now based
in Moscow.\n
Many items were bought in Amsterdam from pharmacologist Albertus Seba (1716) and
anatomist Frederik Ruysch (1717) and formed the basis for the Academy of Sciences. The
Kunstkamera was specially built to house these two extensive collections. A third acquisition
came from Jacob de Wilde, a collector of gems and scientific instruments. Head-physician to the
czar, Robert Erskine, and his secretary Johann Daniel Schumacher were responsible for the
acquisition.\n</string>
    
    <string name="museum_zoological">The Zoological Museum of the Zoological Institute
of the Russian Academy of Sciences is a Russian museum devoted to zoology. It is located
in Saint Petersburg, on Universitetskaya Embankment. It\'s one of the ten largest nature history
museums in the world.\n
\n
Peter the Great\'s Kunstkamera collections included zoological specimens. In 1724 the museum
became a part of the Russian Academy of Sciences. A printed catalogue of the contents was
published in 1742. It listed the zoology, botany, geology and anthropology specimens and
contained an album of etchings of the building and plan of some of its parts. In 1766 Peter Simon
Pallas, member of the Russian Academy of Sciences, was appointed Curator of Zoology. In 1832
the zoological collections were split from the Kunstkamera and in 1896 moved nearby to its
present location in the former southern warehouse of the Saint Petersburg bourse \(constructed in
1826-1832). In 1931 the Zoological Institute was established within the Academy of Sciences,
which included the museum.\n
\n
In the front hall of the museum, with the monument to Karl Ernst von Baer by the entrance, the
exhibition of the zoological collection of the Kunstkamera acquired by Peter the Great in the early
18th century is located, as well as skeletons of cetaceans, including the enormous 27 m
long blue whale in the middle of it, and mounted pinnipeds. In the gallery above the front hall the
entomological collection is displayed. The second and third halls form a long passage with
systematic collections and dioramas dating back to the early 20th century and are situated to the
left of the front hall. The second hall hosts the collection
of fishes, amphibians, reptiles, birds andinvertebrates, mounted or preserved in formalin, and
their skeletons or shells. The collection of mammals, including woolly mammoths, is displayed in
the third hall.</string>

    <string name="palace_moika">The Moika Palace or Yusupov Palace (Russian: Дворец Юсуповых на
        Мойке, literally the Palace of the Yusupovs on the Moika) was once the primary residence in 
        St. Petersburg, Russia of the House of Yusupov. The building was the site of Grigori
        Rasputin\'s murder in the early morning of December 17, 1916.\n
\n
The palace was first built around 1776 by the French architect Jean-Baptiste Vallin de la Mothe.
        Over the years numerous well-known architects worked on the palace, producing a variety of
        architectural styles. A. Mikhailov reconstructed the building during the 1830s when the 
        Yusupovs became owners of the building. This was the period that the palace achieved its
        present-day appearance. \n
\n
From 1830 to 1917, the palace belonged to the House of Yusupov, an immensely wealthy family of
        Russian nobles, known for their philanthropy and art collections. Thus in the time of
        Imperial Russia, the palace became known as the Yusupov Palace.\n
\n
The luxurious interiors of the palace were not inferior to those of contemporary royal palaces.
        More than 40,000 works of art, including works by Rembrandt, jewelry, and sculptures
        decorated the palace. Following the Russian Revolution, the Yusupov art collections were
        nationalized and relocated in the Hermitage and other museums. Ernst Friedrich von Liphart,
        who was the curator of paintings at the Hermitage, had earlier painted the curtain and
        ceiling of the palace theatre.
</string>

    <string name="palace_winter">The Winter Palace (Russian: Зи́мний дворе́ц; IPA: [ˈzʲimnʲɪj dvɐˈrʲɛts
        ]) in Saint Petersburg, Russia, was, from 1732 to 1917, the official residence of the 
        Russian monarchs. Situated between the Palace Embankment and the Palace Square, adjacent
        to the site of Peter the Great\'s original Winter Palace, the present and fourth Winter Palace
        was built and altered almost continuously between the late 1730s and 1837, when it was
        severely damaged by fire and immediately rebuilt. The storming of the palace in 1917 as
        depicted in Soviet paintings and Eisenstein\'s 1927 film October became an iconic symbol of
        the Russian Revolution.\n
\n
The palace was constructed on a monumental scale that was intended to reflect the might and power
        of Imperial Russia. From the palace, the Tsar ruled over 22,400,000 square kilometres
        (8,600,000 sq mi) (almost 1/6 of the Earth\'s landmass) and over 125 million subjects by the
        end of the 19th century. It was designed by many architects, most notably Bartolomeo
        Rastrelli, in what came to be known as the Elizabethan Baroque style. The green-and-white
        palace has the shape of an elongated rectangle, and its principal façade is 250 m long and
        100 ft (30 m) high. The Winter Palace has been calculated to contain 1,786 doors, 1,945
        windows, 1,500 rooms and 117 staircases. The rebuilding of 1837 left the exterior unchanged,
        but large parts of the interior were redesigned in a variety of tastes and styles, leading
        the palace to be described as a \"19th-century palace inspired by a model in Rococo style\".\n
\n
In 1905, the Bloody Sunday massacre occurred when demonstrators marched toward the Winter Palace,
        but by this time the Imperial Family had chosen to live in the more secure and secluded
        Alexander Palace at Tsarskoe Selo, and returned to the Winter Palace only for the most
        formal and rarest state occasions. Following the February Revolution of 1917, the palace
        was for a short time the seat of the Russian Provisional Government, led by Alexander
        Kerensky. Later that same year, the palace was stormed by a detachment of Red Army soldiers
        and sailors—a defining moment in the birth of the Soviet state. On a less glorious note,
        the month-long looting of the palace\'s wine cellars during this troubled period led to what
        has been described as \"the greatest hangover in history\". Today, the restored palace forms
        part of the complex of buildings housing the Hermitage Museum.
</string>

    <string name="palace_pavlovsk">Pavlovsk Palace (Russian: Павловский дворец) is an 18th-century
        Russian Imperial residence built by Catherine the Great for her son,Grand Duke Paul, in 
        Pavlovsk, within Saint Petersburg. After his death, it became the home of his widow, Maria
        Feodorovna. The palace and the large English garden surrounding it are now a Russian state
        museum and public park. \n
\n
In 1777, the Empress Catherine II of Russia gave a parcel of a thousand hectares of forest along the
        winding Slavyanka River, four kilometers from her residence at Tsarskoye Selo, to her son
        and heir Paul I and his wife Maria Feodorovna, to celebrate the birth of their first son,
        the future Alexander I of Russia.\n
\n
At the time the land was given to Paul and Maria Feodorovna, there were two rustic log lodges called
        \'Krik\' and \'Krak.\' Paul and his wife spent the summers of 1777 to 1780 in Krik, while their
        new homes and the garden were being built.\n
\n
They began by building two wooden buildings, one kilometer apart. Paul\'s house, a two-story house in
        the Dutch style, with small gardens, was called \"Marienthal\", or the \"Valley of Maria.\"
        Maria\'s house was a small wooden house with a cupola, flower beds, named \"Paullust\", or
        \"Paul\'s Joy.\" Paul and Maria Feodorovna began to create picturesque \"ruins\", a Chinese
        kiosk, Chinese bridges and classical temples in the English landscape garden style which
        had spread rapidly across Europe in the second half of the 18th century.\n
\n
In 1780, Catherine the Great loaned her official architect, the Scotsman Charles Cameron, to design
        a palace on a hillside overlooking the Slavyanka River, near the site of Marienthal.\n
\n
Cameron had studied under English architect Isaac Ware, who was close to William Kent. Kent
        introduced the Palladian style of architecture into England with his work at Chiswick House
         for Lord Burlington. Through this connection Cameron became familiar with the original
        plans of Palladio, which were in the personal collection of Lord Burlington. This style was
        the major influence on Cameron when he designed Pavlovsk.\n
\n
Cameron began his project not with the palace itself but with two classical pavilions. The first was
        the Temple of Friendship, a circularDorian temple with sixteen columns supporting a low
        dome, containing a statue of Catherine the Great. It was placed at a bend of the Slavyanka
        River, below the future palace, and was surrounded by silver poplars and transplanted
        Siberian pines. The second was the Apollo Colonnade, a double row of columns with an
        entablature, forming a setting for a reproduction of a reproduction of the Belvedere Apollo.
        It was placed at the entrance of the park, and it was made of porous limestone with a coarse
        finish; the surfaces suggest that they had been aged by centuries of weather. At the same
        time the Slavyanka River was dammed, to create a lake which would mirror the facade of the
        palace above.</string>

    <string name="palace_menshikov">The Menshikov Palace (Russian: Меншиковский дворец) is a Petrine
        Baroque edifice in Saint Petersburg, situated onUniversitetskaya Embankment of the Bolshaya
        Neva on Vasilyevsky Island. It was the first stone building in the city. Since 1981, it has
        served as a public museum, a branch of the Hermitage Museum.\n
\n
The palace was founded in 1710 as a residence of Saint Petersburg Governor General Alexander
        Menshikov and built by Italian architects Giovanni Maria Fontana, and, later, German
        architect Gottfried Johann Schädel. It was opened in 1711, but the construction continued
        until 1727 (assisted by Domenico Trezzini, Bartolomeo Rastrelli, Georg Johann Mattarnovy and
         Jean-Baptiste Le Blond), when Menshikov with his family was exiled to Siberia and his
        property was confiscated.\n
\n
In 1731, Cadet Corps were established and occupied the palace and neighboring buildings. At the end
        of the 19th century the Menshikov Palace was restored and became the museum of the Corps.
        In 1924, its collections were moved to the Hermitage and other museums. From 1956-1981 the
        Menshikov Palace was restored again and finally opened to the public as a branch of the
        Hermitage Museum with a collection of Russian art of the late 17th-early 18th century.</string>

    <string name="palace_peterhof">The Peterhof Palace (Russian: Петерго́ф; IPA: [pʲɪtʲɪrˈɡof], Dutch
         for Peter\'s Court) is a series of palaces and gardens located in Petergof, Saint Petersburg,
         Russia, laid out on the orders of Peter the Great. These palaces and gardens are sometimes
        referred as the \"Russian Versailles\". The palace-ensemble along with the city center is
        recognized as a UNESCO World Heritage Site. \n
\n
The dominant natural feature of Peterhof is a sixteen-metre-high bluff lying less than a hundred
        metres from the shore. The so-called Lower Gardens (Nizhny Sad), at 1.02 km² comprising the
        better part of Peterhof\'s land area, are confined between this bluff and the shore,
        stretching east and west for roughly 200 metres. The majority of Peterhof\'s fountains are
        contained here, as are several small palaces and outbuildings. East of the Lower Gardens
        lies the Alexandria Park with 19th-century Gothic Revival structures such as the Kapella.\n
\n
Atop the bluff, near the middle of the Lower Gardens, stands the Grand Palace (Bolshoi Dvorets).
        Behind (south) of it are the comparatively small Upper Gardens (Verhnyy Sad). Upon the
        bluff\'s face below the Palace is the Grand Cascade (Bolshoi Kaskad). This and the Grand
        Palace are the centrepiece of the entire complex. At its foot begins the Sea Channel
        (Morskoi Kanal), one of the most extensive waterworks of the Baroque period, which bisects
        the Lower Gardens.
</string>

    <string name="palace_stroganov">The Stroganov Palace (Russian: Строгановский дворец) is a Late
        Baroque palace at the intersection of the Moika Riverand Nevsky Prospect in St. Petersburg,
         Russia. The palace was built to Bartolomeo Rastrelli\'s designs for Baron Sergei
        Grigoriyevich Stroganov in 1753-1754. The interiors were remodeled by Andrei Voronikhin at
        the turn of the 19th century. \n
\n
The first house for the Stroganovs was built on the site probably in the 1720s. It was a one-storey
        building. Аrchitect Mikhail Zemtsoverected a second, two-storey house on the site in the 1740s.\n
\n
In 1752, Baron Sergei Stroganov commissioned the palace design from Italian architect Bartolomeo
        Rastrelli, then at work extending theCatherine Palace and building the Smolny Convent for 
        Empress Elisabeth. Since the Stroganovs were the richest family in Russia and were related
        to the Empress by marriage, Rastrelli could not turn down the commission and hastily
        prepared a design for thetownhouse.\n
\n
Like the Vorontsov Palace (also designed by Rastrelli for Stroganov\'s in-law Mikhail Vorontsov),
        the Stroganov Palace was not rapidly built. The Main Staircase decorated with marble
        sculptures led to the elegant Grand Hall, which featured a huge painting by Venetian artist
        Giuseppe Valeriani. After Sergei Stroganov\'s death in 1756, the decoration was completed by
        his son Alexander in 1760. Within several years, the new empress, Catherine II introduced the
         Neoclassical taste. The style was also championed by Alexander Stroganov, who became
        President of the Imperial Academy of Arts in 1800.
</string>

    <string name="religion_alexander">Saint Alexander Nevsky Lavra or Saint Alexander Nevsky Monastery was founded by Peter I
of Russia in 1710 at the eastern end of the Nevsky Prospekt in Saint Petersburg supposing
that was the site of the Neva Battle in 1240 when Alexander Nevsky, a prince, defeated the
Swedes; however, the battle actually took place about 12 miles (19 km) away from that site. \"On
April 5, 1713, in St. Petersburg, in the presence of Peter I, the wooden Church of the
Annunciation was consecrated. This day is considered the official founding date of the Alexander
Nevsky Lavra.\" \n
\n
\";The relics of St. Alexander Nevsky were solemnly transferred from Vladimir to the new capital
of Russia September 12, 1724 by decree of Peter the Great.\" Nevsky became patron of the
newly founded Russian capital; however, the massive silver sarcophagus of St. Alexander
Nevsky was relocated during Soviet times to the State Hermitage Museum where it remains
(without the relics) today.\n
\n
In 1797, the monastery was raised to the rank of lavra, making it only the third lavra in
the Russian Orthodox Church that had that designation bestowed upon it, following only the Kiev
Monastery of the Caves and the Trinity Monastery of St Sergius. \n
\n
The monastery grounds contain two baroque churches, designed by father and son Trezzini and
built from 1717–1722 and 1742–1750, respectively; a majestic Neoclassical cathedral, built in
1778–1790 to a design by Ivan Starov and consecrated to the Holy Trinity; and numerous
structures of lesser importance. It also contains the Lazarev and Tikhvin Cemeteries, where
ornate tombs of Leonhard Euler, Mikhail Lomonosov, Alexander Suvorov,Nikolay
Karamzin, Modest Mussorgsky, Pyotr Ilyich Tchaikovsky, Fyodor Dostoevsky, Karl Ivanovic
Rossi, Prince Garsevan Chavchavadze, a Georgian aristocrat, Sergei Witte and other famous
Russians are preserved. \n
\n
During the Revolution, People\'s Commissar of Social Welfare Kollontai wanted to convert the
monastery into a \'sanctuary for war invalids\'; she sent a group of sailors 19 January 1918, who
were met by an angry crowd of worshipers, and after some fighting a priest was shot and killed.
\n
\n
Today Alexander Nevsky Lavra sits on Alexander Nevsky Square, where shoppers can buy
bread baked by the monks. Visitors may also visit the cathedral and cemeteries for a small
admission fee. While many of the grave sites are situated behind large concrete walls, especially
those of famous Russians, many can be seen by passers-by while strolling down Obukovskoy
Oburony Street.</string>

    <string name="religion_isaac">Saint Isaac\'s Cathedral or Isaakievskiy Sobor (Russian: Исаа́киевский Собо́р) in Saint
Petersburg, Russia, is the largest Russian Orthodox cathedral (sobor) in the city. It is the largest
orthodox basilica and the fourth largest (by the volume under the cupola) cathedral in the
world. It is dedicated to Saint Isaac of Dalmatia, a patron saint of Peter the Great, who had been
born on the feast day of that saint. \n
\n
The church on St Isaac\'s Square was ordered by Tsar Alexander I, to replace an earlier
structure by Vincenzo Brenna, and was the fifth consecutive church standing at this place. A
specially appointed commission examined several designs, including that of the French-
born architect Auguste de Montferrand (1786–1858), who had studied in the atelier of
Napoleon\'s designer, Charles Percier. Montferrand\'s design was criticised by some members of
the commission for the dry and allegedly boring rhythm of its four identical pedimented octastyle
porticos. It was also suggested that despite gigantic dimensions, the edifice would look squat and
not very impressive. The members of the commission, which consisted of well-known Russian
architects, were also particularly concerned by necessity to build a new huge building on the old
unsecure foundation. The emperor, who favoured the ponderous Empire style of architecture,
had to step in and solve the dispute in Montferrand\'s favour. \n
\n
The cathedral took 40 years to construct, under Montferrand\'s direction, from 1818 to 1858. To
secure the construction, the cathedral\'s foundation was strengthened by driving 25,000 piles into
the fenland of Saint Petersburg. Innovative methods were created to erect the giant columns of
the portico. The construction costs of the cathedral totalled an incredible sum of 1 000 000
gold rubles. Under the Soviet government, the building was stripped of religious trappings. In
1931, it was turned into the Museum of the History of Religion and Atheism, the dove sculpture
was removed, and replaced by a Foucault pendulum. On April 12, 1931, the first public
demonstration of the Foucault pendulum was held to visualize Copernicus\’s theory. In 1937, the
museum was transformed into the museum of the Cathedral, and former collections were
transferred to the Museum of the History of Religion (located in the Kazan Cathedral). \n
\n
During World War II, the dome was painted over in gray to avoid attracting attention from enemy
aircraft. On its top, in the skylight, a geodesical intersection point was placed, to determine the
positions of German artillery batteries. \n
\n
With the fall of communism, the museum was removed and regular worship activity has resumed
in the cathedral, but only in the left-hand side chapel. The main body of the cathedral is used for
services on feast days only. \n
\n
As of 2015, the church is still a museum.</string>

    <string name="religion_kazan">Kazan Cathedral or Kazanskiy Kafedralniy Sobor (Russian: Каза́нский кафедра́льный
собо́р), also known as the Cathedral of Our Lady of Kazan, is a cathedral of the Russian
Orthodox Church on the Nevsky Prospekt inSaint Petersburg. It is dedicated to Our Lady of
Kazan, probably the most venerated icon in Russia. \n
\n
The construction was started in 1801 and continued for ten years while being supervised
by Alexander Sergeyevich Stroganov. Upon its completion in 1811, the new temple replaced the
Church of Nativity of the Theotokos, which was disassembled when the Kazan Cathedral was
consecrated. \n
\n
It was modelled by Andrey Voronikhin after the St. Peter\'s Basilica in Rome. Some art historians
assert that Emperor Paul intended to build a similar church on the other side of Nevsky Prospect
that would mirror the Kazan Cathedral but his plans failed to materialize. Although the Russian
Orthodox Church strongly disapproved of the plans to create a replica of a Catholic basilica in
Russia\'s then capital, several courtiers supported Voronikhin\'s Empire Style design. \n
\n
After Napoleon invaded Russia in 1812, and the commander-in- chief Mikhail Kutuzov asked Our
Lady of Kazan for help, the church\'s purpose was to be altered. The Patriotic War over, the
cathedral was perceived primarily as a memorial to the Russian victory against
Napoleon. Kutuzov himself was interred in the cathedral in 1813; and Alexander Pushkin wrote
celebrated lines meditating over his sepulchre. In 1815, keys to seventeen cities and eight
fortresses were brought by the victorious Russian army from Europe and placed in the
cathedral\'s sacristy. In 1837, Boris Orlovsky designed two bronze statues of Kutuzov
and Barclay de Tolly in front of the cathedral. \n
\n
In 1876, the Kazan demonstration, the first political demonstration in Russia, took place in front
of the church. After the Russian Revolution of 1917, the cathedral was closed. In 1932 it was
reopened as the pro-Marxist \"Museum of the History of Religion and Atheism.\" Services were
resumed in 1992, and four years later the cathedral was returned to the Russian Orthodox
Church. Now it is the mother cathedral of the metropolis of St. Petersburg. \n
\n
The cathedral\'s interior, with its numerous columns, echoes the exterior colonnade and is
reminiscent of a palatial hall, being 69 metres in length and 62 metres in height. The interior
features numerous sculptures and icons created by the best Russian artists of the day. A
wrought iron grille separating the cathedral from a small square behind it is sometimes cited as
one of the finest ever created. \n
\n The cathedral\'s huge bronze doors are one of three copies of the original doors of the
Baptistry in Florence, Italy (the other two are in San Francisco and on the Baptistry itself).</string>

    <string name="religion_kronstadt">The Naval cathedral of Saint Nicholas in Kronstadt is a Russian Orthodox cathedral built in
1903–1913 as the main church of the Russian Navy and dedicated to all fallen seamen. The
cathedral was closed in 1929, was converted to a cinema, a House of Officers (1939) and a
museum of the Navy (1980). \n
\n
The Russian Orthodox Church reinstalled the cross on the main dome in 2002 and served the
first Divine Liturgy in the cathedral in 2005. In 2013, the Patriarch of Russia, with Prime
Minister Dmitriy Medvedevand his spouse attending, conducted the ceremony of
grand reconsecration in the now fully restored cathedral. \n
\n
The first Orthodox church in Kronstadt was built in 1728–31. The wooden church remained the
main place of worship in Russia\'s largest naval base until 1840, when the counterweights
balancing the church bells broke through the rotting floors and seriously damaged the belltower
structure. Emperor Nicholas I personally ordered the closure of the unsafe church and it was
demolished in 1841. For the next half century worship occurred in temporary locations — in
hospitals, barracks and even rented private houses; a temporary wooden church built in 1861
was inadequate for the ten thousand Kronstadt seamen from the start. Numerous Navy requests
for construction funding were turned down or simply left unanswered, despite the fact that the
cost of building a large contemporary cathedral (200 to 500 thousand roubles) was less than
10% of a pre-dreadnought battleship\’s cost (RUB4 to 6 million). \n
\n
Construction management, extremely centralized until the reign of Alexander II, was gradually
decentralized in the 1880s–1890s. The right to initiate individual construction projects passed
from the Emperor himself to imperial ministers and department chiefs. In 1896 admiral Pavel
Tyrtov, director of the Imperial Russian Navy Ministry, started preparations to build a cathedral in
Kronstadt in earnest. Tyrtov insisted that the cathedral be built on the site identified nearly two
centuries earlier by Peter I and reasoned that it should not cost more than the
new Kharkov cathedral (200,000 roubles).</string>

    <string name="religion_savior">The Church of the Savior on Spilled Blood (Russian: Церковь Спаса на Крови, Tserkov\ʹ
Spasa na Krovi) is one of the main sights of St. Petersburg, Russia. Other names include
the Church on Spilled Blood(Russian: Церковь на Крови, Tserkov\’ na Krovi), the Temple of the
Savior on Spilled Blood (Russian: Храм Спаса на Крови, Khram Spasa na Krovi), and
the Cathedral of the Resurrection of Christ (Russian: Собор Воскресения Христова, Sobor
Voskreseniya Khristova). \n
\n
This Church was built on the site where Emperor Alexander II was fatally wounded in March
1881.The church was built between 1883 and 1907. The construction was funded by the imperial
family. \n
\n
Construction began in 1883 during the reign of Alexander III. The church was dedicated to be a
memorial to his father, Alexander II. Estimates suggest that the construction cost 4.5 million
rubles. The construction was completed during the reign of Nicholas II in 1907. Funding was
provided by the Imperial family with the support of many private donors. \n
\n
The Church is prominently situated along the Griboedov Canal; paved roads run along both sides
of the canal. On March 13, 1881 (Julian date: March 1), as Tsar Alexander\'s carriage passed
along the embankment, a grenade thrown by an anarchist conspirator exploded. The tsar,
shaken but unhurt, got out of the carriage and started to remonstrate with the presumed culprit. A
second conspirator took the chance to throw another bomb, killing himself and mortally wounding
the tsar. The tsar, bleeding heavily, was taken back to the Winter Palace where he died a few
hours later. \n
\n
A temporary shrine was erected on the site of the attack while plans and fundraising for a more
permanent memorial were undertaken. In order to build a permanent shrine on the exact spot
where the assassination took place, it was decided to narrow the canal so that the section of
road on which the tsar had been driving could be included within the walls of the church. An
elaborate shrine was constructed at the end of the church opposite the altar, on the exact place
of Alexander\'s death. It is embellished with topaz, lazurite and other semi-precious stones,
making a striking contrast with the simple cobblestones of the old road, which are exposed in the
floor of the shrine.</string>

    <string name="religion_smolny">This Russian Orthodox convent was built to house Elizabeth, the daughter of Peter the Great.
After she was disallowed succession to the throne, she opted to become a nun. However her
Imperial predecessor,Ivan VI was overthrown during a coup d\'état (carried out by the royal
guards in 1741). Elizabeth then decided against entering monastic life and accepted the offer of
the Russian throne and work on the convent continued with her royal patronage. \n
\n
The convent\'s main church (catholicon or sobor), a blue-and- white building, is considered to be
one of the architectural masterpieces of the Italian architect Francesco Bartolomeo Rastrelli, who
also redesigned the Winter Palace, and created the Grand Catherine Palace (Yekaterininsky)
in Tsarskoye Selo (Pushkin), the Grand Palace in Peterhof and many other major St. Petersburg
landmarks. \n
\n
The Cathedral is the centerpiece of the convent, built by Rastrelli between 1748 and 1764. The
projected bell-tower was to become the tallest building in St. Petersburg and, at the time, all of
Russia. Elizabeth\'s death in 1762 prevented Rastrelli from completing this grand design. \n
\n
When Catherine II assumed the throne, it was found that the new Empress strongly disapproved
of the baroque style, and funding that had supported the construction of the convent rapidly ran
out. Rastrelli was unable to build the huge bell-tower he had planned and unable to finish the
interior of the cathedral. The building was only finished in 1835 by Vasily Stasovwith the addition
of a neo-classical interior to suit the changed architectural tastes at the time. The Cathedral
was consecrated on 22 July 1835; its main altar was dedicated to theResurrection and the two
side altars were dedicated to St. Mary Magdalene and Righteous Elizabeth. The church was
closed by the Soviet authorities in 1923. It was looted and allowed to decay until 1982, when it
became a Concert Hall. \n
\n
Today, Smolny Cathedral is used primarily as a concert hall and the surrounding convent
buildings house various offices and government institutions. In addition, the faculties of
sociology, political science and international relations of the Saint Petersburg State University are
located in some of the buildings surrounding the cathedral. \n
\n
The nearby Smolny Institute is named after the convent. \n
\n
The name \"Smolny\" derives from the location, in the early days of St. Petersburg the place at
the edge of the city where pitch (\"smola\" in Russian) was processed for use in shipbuilding and
maintenance. As a result, the locale was called \"smolny\" - the place of pitch.</string>

    <string name="theatre_alexandrinsky">The Alexandrinsky Theatre (Russian: Александринский театр) or Russian State Pushkin
Academy Drama Theater (Российский государственный академический театр драмы им. А.
С. Пушкина) is a theatre in Saint Petersburg, Russia. \n
\n
The Alexandrinsky Theatre was built for the Imperial troupe of Petersburg (Imperial troupe was
founded in 1756). \n
\n
The theatre was opened on 31 August (12 September), 1832. \n
\n
Since 1832, the theatre has occupied an Empire-style building that Carlo Rossi designed. It was
built in 1828-1832 on Alexandrinsky Square (now Ostrovsky Square), which is situated
on Nevsky Prospekt between the National Library of Russia and Anichkov Palace. The theatre
and the square were named after Empress consort Alexandra Feodorovna. The building is part
of the UNESCO World Heritage Site Historic Centre of Saint Petersburg and Related Groups of
Monuments. \n
\n
It was one of the many theatres of the Imperial troupe. Dramas, operas and ballets were on the
stage. Only in 1880-ies, the theatre has become dramatic and tragedy filled. \n
\n
The premières of numerous Russian plays have been performed at the stage of the
Alexandrinsky, including plays by Alexandr Griboyedov, Alexander Ostrovsky, and Anton
Chekhov. Famous directors who have staged work there include Vsevolod Meyerhold, Grigori
Kozintsev, Georgy Tovstonogov, and Nikolay Akimov. \n
\n
On 30 August 2006 the theatre reopened after a reconstruction.</string>

    <string name="theatre_hermitage">The Hermitage Theatre (Russian: Эрмитажный Театр, tr. Èrmitážnyj Teátr; IPA: [ɪrʲmʲɪ\ˈtaʐnɨj
tʲɪ\ˈatər]) in Saint Petersburg, Russia is one of five Hermitage buildings lining the Palace
Embankment of the Neva River. \n
\n
The Hermitage Theatre was the second theatre of the Winter Palace. It replaced the Russian
Imperial Theater, which operated from 1764 until 1783. The Hermitage Theatre was built
between 1783 and 1787 at the behest of Catherine the Great to a Palladian design by Giacomo
Quarenghi. The crumbling Third Winter Palace of Peter the Great was demolished to make room
for the new structure, although its old foundations are still visible in the ground floor. Quarenghi\'s
designs for the theatre were engraved and published in 1787, earning him a European
reputation. \n
\n
The semicircular auditorium is decorated with color marble and surrounded with ten niches for
statues of Apollo and the muses. As the interior has never been overhauled, the original stage
machinery remains in situ, but the elaborate sets, an acclaimed work of the Italian artist Pietro
Gonzaga (1751-1831), were lost during the years of Soviet neglect. \n
\n
The ceremonial opening of the theatre took place on 22 November 1785. Though the auditorium
could seat no more than 250 spectators, it was often overcrowded. Usually, the performance
would be attended by several dozen aristocratic spectators, all invited by the monarch herself. As
a sign of gratitude, a separate loge was reserved for the architect Quarenghi and his family. In
the 19th century, selected members of the diplomatic corps were admitted to the theatre as well.
\n
\n
Although the building was used to entertain the imperial family until the Russian Revolution, it
came to be viewed as a rare monument to Catherine\'s personal tastes and affections. The
empress brought out several comedies specifically to be staged in this theatre, which also saw
the premieres of Domenico Cimarosa\'s operas composed to her own librettos. As for the
costumes, they were chosen from a 15,000-dress personal wardrobe of the late Empress
Elizabeth. \n
\n
Mathilde Kschessinska, Anna Pavlova, and Fyodor Chaliapin were among the great artists who
performed at the Hermitage Theatre for the last Russian tsar. Among the ballets performed there
was the premiere of Marius Petipa\'s Harlequinade, in 1900. The Bolsheviks closed the theatre
and utilised the building for administrative purposes. It was not until 1991 that performances were
resumed on this stage, with the likes of Svyatoslav Richter, Mstislav Rostropovich and Yelena
Obraztsova appearing as guest stars.</string>

    <string name="theatre_mariinsky">The Mariinsky Theatre (Russian: Мариинский театр, Mariinskiy Teatr, also
spelled Maryinsky, Mariyinsky) is a historic theatre of opera and ballet in Saint
Petersburg, Russia. Opened in 1860, it became the preeminent music theatre of late 19th
century Russia, where many of the stage masterpieces of Tchaikovsky, Mussorgsky,
and Rimsky-Korsakov received their premieres. Through most of the Soviet era, it was known as
the Kirov Theatre. Today, the Mariinsky Theatre is home to the Mariinsky Ballet, Mariinsky Opera
and Mariinsky Orchestra. Since Yuri Temirkanov\'s retirement in 1988, the conductor Valery
Gergiev has served as the theatre\'s general director.
The Imperial drama, opera and ballet troupe in Saint Petersburg was established in 1783, at the
behest of Catherine the Great, although an Italian ballet troupe had performed at the Russian
court since the early 18th century. Originally, the ballet and opera performances were given in
the wooden Karl Knipper Theatre on Tsaritsa Meadow, near the present-day Tripartite
Bridge (also known as the Little Theatre or the Maly Theatre). The Hermitage Theatre, next door
to the Winter Palace, was used to host performances for an elite audience of aristocratic guests
invited by the Empress. \n
\n
A permanent theatre building for the new company of opera and ballet artists was designed
by Antonio Rinaldi and opened in 1783. Known as the Imperial Bolshoi Kamenny Theatre the
structure was situated on Carousel Square, which was renamed Theatre Square in honour of the
building. Both names - \"Kamenny\" (Russian word for \"stone\") and \"Bolshoi\" (Russian word
for \"big\") - were coined to distinguish it from the wooden Little Theatre. In 1836, the Bolshoi
Kamenny Theatre was renovated to a design by Albert Cavos (son of Catterino Cavos, an opera
composer), and served as the principal theatre of the Imperial Ballet and opera. \n
\n
On 29 January 1849, the Equestrian circus (Конный цирк) opened on Theatre Square. This was
also the work of the architect Cavos. The building was designed to double as a theatre. It was a
wooden structure in the then-fashionable neo-Byzantine style. Ten years later, when this circus
burnt down, Albert Cavos rebuilt it as an opera and ballet house with the largest stage in the
world. With a seating capacity of 1,625 and a U-shaped Italian-style auditorium, the theatre
opened on 2 October 1860 with a performance of A Life for the Tsar. The new theatre was
named Mariinsky after its imperial patroness, Empress Maria Alexandrovna.</string>

    <string name="theatre_mikhailovsky">The Mikhailovsky Theatre (Russian: Миха́йловский теа́тр) is one of Russia\'s
oldest opera and ballet houses. It was founded in 1833 and is situated in a historical building on
the Arts Square in St. Petersburg. It is named after Grand Duke Michael Pavlovich of Russia. \n
\n
The theatre was established in 1833 by decree of Tsar Nicholas I. \n
\n
Before the 1917 Revolution, the Mikhailovsky did not have its own resident company.
Performances were given either by a French company, hired by the Russian Imperial Theatres or
at the end of the century by the Mariinsky Theatre and Alexandrinsky Theatrecompanies. Most of
the great French actors of the period performed at the theatre: Those appearing included Jeanne
Sylvanie Arnould-Plessy, Rachel Félix, Lucien Guitry and Sarah Bernhardt, as well as singers
such as Hortense Schneider. Both classical and contemporary authors and composers had their
works produced to great acclaim in French. Plays by Molière, Victor Hugo, Victorien Sardou,
and Alexandre Dumas, fils and operettas by Jacques Offenbach were praised by the
intelligentsia and the Russian aristocracy, such as Tolstoy and Tchaikovsky. \n
\n
When the Bolsheviks took power, the French company was forced to leave Russia. In 1917 the
Mikhailovsky Theatre was closed. On March 6, 1918 the theatre was reopened as an opera
theatre. Shortly afterwards the Mikhailovsky started changing its names. In 1918-1920, it was
called the Ex-Mikhailovsky Theatre. In 1920 it was renamed to the State Academic Comic Opera
Theatre, in 1921 the theatre changed its name to the Maly Operny (Maly Opera Theatre). In
1926 it got the name of the Leningrad State Academic Maly Opera Theatre, MALEGOT for short.
New management and artists followed. In 1920-1930 the Maly Operny established itself as one
of the leading experimental stages in Russian new musical theatre. Shostakovich made his debut
at the Maly Operny: Samuil Samosud conducted world premiere performances of his The
Nose and Lady Macbeth of the Mtsensk District, the famous Vsevolod Meyerhold production
of The Queen of Spades was staged there, and the world premiere of Prokofiev\'s epic opera War
and Peacetook place on the theatre\'s stage on June 12, 1946. In 1930s Russian
choreographer Fyodor Lopukhov founded the ballet company of the theatre. The first ballet
premiere, Harlequinade, choreographed by Lopukhov, took place on June 6, 1933. \n
\n
From 1989 to 2007 the theatre bore the name of Modest Mussorgsky, subsequently returning to
its original name the Mikhailovsky Theatre.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>
</resources>
